# **lacob Giamanco**

El Cajon 92021

6195922261

- https://jgiamanco.now.sh
- jacobdeansd@gmail.com

jgiamanco

in jacob-giamanco

### **OBJECTIVE**

Highly adaptable and hard working web developer with strong problem solving skills. Experienced with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, and API integration. With a goal to create high quality responsive web applications with scalability and speed.

#### **PERSONAL WORK**

#### Portfolio Website

https://jgiamanco.now.sh

- Tech Used: React, JavaScript, CSS3, Bootstrap, Jquery, HTML/CSS, and JSON.
- Get to know me and see some of my work.

#### **NFL Rosters**

https://nfl-rosters.now.sh

- Tech Used: React, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML/CSS, React-Dom, Semantic UI, API.
- Search for your favorite NFL players using an easy to navigate web app

### CRWN - Ecommerce web app

https://crwnclothingco.netlify.app

- Tech Used: React, JavaScript, Firebase, Redux, Redux-Sagas, GraphQL, React-Dom, React-Router, React persist, HTML/CSS/Sass, Reselect, Node.js, Stripe API.
- E-commerce web app Google sign in and stripe integration for payments.

#### CryptoClash Web App

https://cryptoclash.herokuapp.com/#

- Tech Used: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, Web Sockets, AWS servers, multiple APIs
- team collaboration website built around cryptocompare and news APIs.

### Face Detection Web app

https://facialdetection.netlify.app/

- Tech Used: React, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Clarifai API, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express.
- Upload any photo and watch as the app detects all of the faces.

### Advanced-React-CLI - Open Source Collaboration

https://www.npmjs.com/package/advanced-react-cli

• Added logic to the CLI Input questions, allowing for more possibilities of user responses.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### The Marketing Department - Remote

Web Designer - Contract

(July 2020 - Present)

- Designed full website mockup for client approval
- Utilized custom CSS within Divi Builder to alter ordering of elements dependent on screen size.
- Increased design process speed by %20 allowing other designers to work on other mockups.

#### iTourMobile - Remote

Front End Web Developer - Contract

(June 2020 - July 2020)

- Sped up future development by developing reusable components using Next.js.
- Increased page speed by deferring all videos and below the fold images.
- Completed the redesign of the company's mobile application website.

### BlueGrace Logistics - Remote

(August 2019 - March 2020)

Software Designer - Contract • Created high-fidelity prototypes for developers and invested individuals to view all functional components of the proprietary application.

- Promoted to sole Software Designer for the entire enterprise software redesign.
- Proactively communicated with clients clarifying the overall vision of the design and any necessary updates.

#### Upwork/Client Work - San Diego, CA Full Stack Web Developer/Designer

(March 2019 - Present)

- Created a responsive website for a start-up Real Estate CRM software company
- Fine tuned the UI, SEO, and UX of a cryptocurrency tracking website.
- Helped troubleshoot video playback errors on a photographer's professional website.

# Jacob Dean Photography

Photographer/Videographer/Owner

(March 2018 - Present)

- Single handedly filmed And edited wedding videos with multiple camera setups. Collaborated with photographers and vendors to host two themed workshops.
- Decreased editing time by developing numerous presets and workflow automations.

React

Expert

Novice

SemanticUI

Intermediate

# **EDUCATION**

CERTIFICATIONS

Grossmont College Associates in Fine Art Photography

(August 2009 - June 2013)

# Certificate #UC-SFDT8KW0

Full Stack Web Development Zero to Mastery Academy

JavaScript Certificate

July 2019 SoloLearn Certificate #1024-13513674

May 2020

June 2019

HTML5 Certificate

SoloLearn Certificate #1014-13513674

#### **TECH SKILLS** JavaScript

Intermediate

**Bootstrap** Intermediate

Intermediate HTML5 Expert CSS3 Expert TypeScript

Node.js Intermediate Python Novice Sass Novice Intermediate **API Integration** Next.js

Intermediate Intermediate **REST API** SQL Intermediate Intermediate PHP Wordpress Intermediate Novice PostgreSQL Git Expert Intermediate

**jQuery** Redux Intermediate Novice GraphQL Firebase Intermediate Novice **AWS Express** Intermediate Novice **Data Visualization JSON** 

# **OTHER SKILLS**

Adobe Creative Cloud Microsoft Office

**Figma** 

Slack/Discord/Teams

Trello/Asana

**Strong Communication Fast Learning** 

**Hard Working Detail Oriented Problem Solver**